

Shrikanth Achar K **UI UX Designer** 

### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a passionate UI/UX designer with 14 yrs of experience. I evaluate UI/UX with my frontend coding skills. My passion for art results in visually stunning and intuitive UX designs. Let's collaborate to create meaningful digital experiences that leave a lasting impact.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Infosys 09, 2016 - Present Sr. Lead UX Design

**HCLTech** 02, 2015 - 09, 2016 Lead - Engineer

🧽 тномsоn reuters 08, 2010 - 02, 2015 Engineer - Dev

# **CONTACT**

acharshrikanth@gmail.com +91 9535621589

Karnataka, India.

For my portfolio, visit acharshrikanth.github.io

## **TOOLS**

Figma

Sketch

Adobe XD

Photoshop, Krita, GIMP

Adobe Illustrator, Inkscape

Miro, Mural, Confluence

Invision

# **DOMAINS**

Order Management
Business Operations
Banking & Finance
Communication Services
Logistics & Distribution
Health Care

#### **SKILLS**

User Research Analysis
Interaction Design
Wireframing & Prototyping
Visual Design & Illustrations
Information Architecture
Usability Testing
Design System
Story Boarding
Coding & Dev. Knowledge
Collaboration & Communication

#### **PROJECTS**

**Order Management System:** Collaborated with the PO's and created UI screens for worlds leading luxury car manufacturers.

**Remote work & collaboration:** Brainstormed with the team to design the new app for a govt. body of foreign country.

**Banking & Finance:** Managed project independently, handling requirements and delivering diverse UX design options.

**Enterprise Resource Planning:** Facilitated client workshops, gained insights of system issues, created elegant UI designs.

**Chatbot Assistant:** With heuristic evaluation, created intuitive interaction that impressed clients and led to additional projects.

White Paper Document: Created visual diagrams of comprehensive technical white paper document which simplified the complex technical concepts.

Stock Broking Application: Worked for multiple clients on this.

# **CERTIFICATION**

Strategic Insights, Practice, and Impact - RISD (May 2023)

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering in Info. Science - NMAMIT, Nitte. (VTU)